<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Olive &amp; Mango</title>
    <description>A lifestyle blog on easy to make food, travel and overall well-being. Recipes range from Greek, Caribbean and anything that is wholesome and delicious. Tips for those living in Trinidad and Tobago as well as Toronto, Canada.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 09:37:34 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 09:37:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Deliciously Light And Airy Pumpkin Tart</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was the most different take on pumpkin pie that I ever tasted and I have to say I prefer it to the rest.  I love the tart crust with the light and airy filling that has a really nice richness without being overly heavy.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_07_pumpkin_tart_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Tart&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recipe is from Christopher Kimball’s book Milk Street that we did for #rainydaybitescookbookclub. It was the only recipe challenge I could join in on (due to lack of time) for that month and I’m so glad i did.  It was a yummy one. I used my tart recipe because it’s super simple and minimal in ingredients.  His sounded very interesting. He uses a frozen cornstarch paste in the crust mixture which is suppose to trap moisture and prevent if from acting with the gluten in the flour to help get a more tender crust. You will have to check out his recipe from the book or on line to get that recipe.  I thought the pâté sablée worked perfectly. A tender and flaky crust.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_07_pumpkin_tart_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Tart&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of browning the pumpkin and the sugar together reminded me of browning meat in Trini style stew chicken. It yields a really nice caramel colour and a deeper flavour. Mine turned out a little lighter than the rest that participated probably because I used homemade pumpkin purée and our pumpkin here is a bit of a different variety.  Anyways, regardless of how deep the colour is or gets, I found mine lightened a few shades after adding the sour cream into the mix (the sour cream that I used as a substitute for creme fraiche which I couldn’t get my hands on and had no time experiment making homemade). I also used a medium brown sugar and not a dark one which could have added to the lighter filling.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_07_pumpkin_tart_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Tart&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flavour was still the same and this will be on repeat for sure. Could not get enough of that creamy light pumpkin filling with that crisp tart crust. Not too sweet and just great textures happening.  Hope you give it a try and I would love to know how yours turned out!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_07_pumpkin_tart_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Tart&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the crust - pâté sablée&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9 inch circular pan tart or 14 X 4.5 inch rectangular tart pan with removable bottoms -or I also use a springform pan lined with parchment paper if you don’t have a tart pan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 stick of butter room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup of powdered sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg yolk at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1¼ cups of all purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp milk – to add to the dough if needed
* For GF replace AP flour with 1 cup of GF flour blend plus ¼-½ cup of almond meal or ground almonds walnuts or hazelnuts
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the filling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15-ounce can or just under 2 cups of pumpkin puree (homemade recipe below)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup packed dark brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup bourbon or orange juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8-ounce container (1 cup) crème fraîche – I used sour cream as a substitute&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ teaspoon kosher salt
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the crust&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl beat the sugar and butter until well combined and then add the yolk and continue to mix until well incorporated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the flour and salt just enough for all the flour to be incorporated. No need to over-mix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scrape the dough out of bowl onto a piece of plastic wrap and gather the dough and form it into a circular disc or a rectangular one depending on which pan you are using. Wrap it tight and refrigerate for at least one hour up to 2 days. Can also be frozen for up to a month. If using from frozen, allow to thaw overnight in the fridge before using.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the dough from fridge and let it rest for a few minutes to make it easier to roll.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove the dough from the plastic and place it between to sheets of parchment or wax paper to roll it with ease. Roll it out evenly to the size of the tart pan – use the removable bottom as a guide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once rolled out peel the top layer of paper off and invert the dough into the pan. Peel away the last layer of paper and fit the dough into the pan pressing it into the shape of the pan all around. Trim any edges off and reshape dough by pressing it if needed if there is a tear or a thin part.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrap the pan and refrigerate for 30 minutes and in the meantime preheat the oven to 375 ° F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the tart on a baking sheet. Line the top of the tart with parchment and fill with pie weights (or dry beans like I used) and blind bake for approx 20-30 minutes or until the edges begin to turn golden then remove and place on a cooling rack and allow to cool while you make your filling (tart has not finished baking – will finish baking with the filling)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the filling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While the tart crust bakes, in a medium nonstick skillet over medium-high heat, combine the pumpkin and brown sugar. Cook, stirring frequently, until the mixture is thickened, dark and leaves a film on the pan, about 10 minutes. Transfer to a 2-cup liquid measuring cup and the total mixture should be 1½ cups.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once the tart bakes remove and set aside on a cooling rack and reduce oven temperature to 325 ° F&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the bourbon or orange juice to the skillet, return to medium-high heat and stir, scraping up any browned bits; add to the pumpkin mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a food processor, combine the pumpkin mixture and crème fraîche or sour cream and process a few pulses until smooth. Scrape down the bowl, add the eggs and salt, then process until smooth, about 1 minute. Pour the filling into the warm crust, smoothing the top. Bake on the baking sheet on the middle rack until the edges start to puff and crack and the centre sets, 30 to 35 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cool in the pan on a wire rack for at least 30 minutes. Serve warm or at room temperature.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;homemade-pumpkin-purée&quot;&gt;Homemade Pumpkin Purée&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients-1&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;1 whole pumpkin 4-6 lbs or cut pumpkin pieces&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pinch of salt
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions-1&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400 ° F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line one or two baking sheets with parchment paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice pumpkin open and scoop out the seeds and fibers (reserve seeds for roasting or something else at another time) and cut up into 1-½ inch square pieces removing the skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrange the pieces on baking sheet or sheets and sprinkle with salt and then roast them for 20-40 minutes until fork or knife can easily be inserted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let sheet cool on cooling rack until you pumpkin can be handled and then transfer it all to a food processor and process until the flesh is smooth. Store in the fridge for up to one week and freeze for up to 3 months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* You can also cut the whole pumpkin in half and roast pieces whole but this takes longer to roast and more work to scrape off the flesh from the skin after. I do both and result is the same it just depends on how much time I have on hand and how lazy I am to chop and peel the pumpkin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* you can also boil the pumpkin in water until softened and water evaporates but I prefer roasting it because it develops a unique sweetness and a nuttiness as well
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_07_pumpkin_tart_6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Tart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pumpkin-tart</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pumpkin-tart</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pumpkin Espresso Bundt Cake With A Chocolate Espresso Rum Glaze</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a wonderful bundt cake that we really enjoyed. The combo of it and that luscious glaze was on point.  I did have to make it three times to get it right and the way I wanted it though.  There was just something wrong with it texturally.  Nothing wrong with the recipe at all but I think sometimes variations in flours can make a difference. One of the biggest differences too was that I used homemade pumpkin purée. Maybe the slight extra moisture in the pumpkin was what was throwing off the texture.  Anyways with some very minor tweaks the third time really was a charm and it turned out just the way I wanted.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_05_pumpkin_esspresso_bundt_cake_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Espresso Bundt Cake With A Chocolate Espresso Rum Glaze&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original recipe called for the sugar – coffee swirl to be almost tossed in streusel like – that didn’t work for me because that was another factor affecting the texture.  The pictures of it in the original recipe looked perfect and had a beautiful swirl through the cake.  I couldn’t achieve that at all with the way the recipe instructed. I don’t know why and I likely was doing something wrong but whatever it was it wasn’t working for me so I mixed the sugar coffee mixture into some of the batter and then layered it and it turned in not the swirl effect I wanted and the texture was just right.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_05_pumpkin_esspresso_bundt_cake_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Espresso Bundt Cake With A Chocolate Espresso Rum Glaze&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cake itself isn’t as heavy as some bundts can be. Its a little on the lighter side and would be perfect with a cup of coffee accentuating the expresso in it even further. It’s lightly spiced which goes so well with the pumpkin.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_05_pumpkin_esspresso_bundt_cake_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Espresso Bundt Cake With A Chocolate Espresso Rum Glaze&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pièce de résistance is really the glaze! It’s not only fabulous on this cake but eaten by the  spoonful and I definitely see this glaze over rum and raisin ice cream, waffles and so much more!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_05_pumpkin_esspresso_bundt_cake_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Espresso Bundt Cake With A Chocolate Espresso Rum Glaze&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty simple bundt to make with so much flavour and I know you will love it just as much as we did along with some of our neighbours who we shared all three bundts with. You won’t regret making that glaze either! Enjoy!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_05_pumpkin_esspresso_bundt_cake_6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Espresso Bundt Cake With A Chocolate Espresso Rum Glaze&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes one 10 cup bundt cake or 3 minis&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the cake&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1¼ cups of pumpkin purée (homemade recipe below)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup of coconut oil or vegetable oil of choice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of coconut sugar or brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup of granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups of all purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp of of baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp ground allspice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp of ground ginger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp ground nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp ground clove&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A pinch of salt
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the espresso filling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/3 cup of coconut sugar or brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp of espresso powder or instant coffee powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ tsp ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp of cocoa powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup of cake batter
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the chocolate espresso rum glaze&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2/3 cup semisweet chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 ½ tbsp of dark rum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp of vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp of espresso powder of instant coffee powder
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the bundt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preheat oven to 350 ° F and heavily grease your pan or pans (every nook and cranny) and lightly dust with a bit of flour and set aside&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a medium sized bowl whisk together the flour, baking powder, baking soda, salt and spices and set aside&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a small bowl whisk together all the dry ingredients for the espresso filling and set aside&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a large mixing bowl beat together the pumpkin purée, eggs, oil, both sugars, and the vanilla extract until well blended. Slowly beat in the dry ingredients until you have a smooth batter and everything is incorporated.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remove approx 1 cup of cake batter and whisk it together with the sugar and espresso filling until chocolatey and smooth&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fill the pan/pans with 1/3 of the batter, then pour in half the espresso filling over the batter.  Spoon over another third of the batter over that and then pour the rest of the espresso filling over it. Spoon over the last bit of batter and smooth with a spatula or the back of a spoon.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Place pan on a baking sheet  and bake for 50 - 60 minutes or until done and toothpick inserted comes out clean. Allow cake to cool in pan for 15 minutes before inverting onto a cooling rack to cool the rest of the way
(my mini bundts took approx 15 minutes less time to bake).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;for the glaze&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a small sauce pan over low heat melt the chocolate chips and whisk  together with the cream, coffee and vanilla extract.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once it’s smooth take off the heat and stir in the rum.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow to cool for a few minutes before pouring it over the cake so that it has a thicker consistency and is easier to pour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_05_pumpkin_esspresso_bundt_cake_7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Espresso Bundt Cake With A Chocolate Espresso Rum Glaze&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Pastry Affair
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;homemade-pumpkin-purée&quot;&gt;Homemade Pumpkin Purée&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients-1&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 whole pumpkin 4-6 lbs or cut pumpkin pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pinch of salt&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;directions-1&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400 ° F&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Line one or two baking sheets with parchment paper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slice pumpkin open and scoop out the seeds and fibers (reserve seeds for roasting or something else at another time) and cut up into 1-½ inch square pieces removing the skin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrange the pieces on baking sheet or sheets and sprinkle with salt and then roast them for 20-40 minutes until fork or knife can easily be inserted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let sheet cool on cooling rack until you pumpkin can be handled and then transfer it all to a food processor and process until the flesh is smooth. Store in the fridge for up to one week and freeze for up to 3 months.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* You can also cut the whole pumpkin in half and roast pieces whole but this takes longer to roast and more work to scrape off the flesh from the skin after. I do both and result is the same it just depends on how much time I have on hand and how lazy I am to chop and peel the pumpkin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;# you can also boil the pumpkin in water until softened and water evaporates but I prefer roasting it because it develops a unique sweetness and a nuttiness as well.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_05_pumpkin_esspresso_bundt_cake_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pumpkin Espresso Bundt Cake With A Chocolate Espresso Rum Glaze&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 20:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pumpkin-espresso-bundt-cake</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pumpkin-espresso-bundt-cake</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beet And Goat Cheese Salad With A Passion Fruit Dressing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love beets for their earthy and sweet flavour and they make every meal they are in hearty. Roasting them makes them even sweeter tasting. They are so good for you too! They are wonderful in a salad and great with a tart dressing.  This salad places the beets among fabulous ingredients that bring out the beets finer qualities.  Nigella Lawson is a genius and this is a classic example of that. Her pairing the beets with the passion fruit is perfect. The passion fruit lends its tartness well and the goat cheese adds creaminess and a salty tangy edge.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_03_beet_salad_passionfruit_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beet salad with passionfruit dressing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just made a couple of tweaks to the recipe out of necessity more than anything else. I used fresh chopped mint instead of dill because I didn’t have any at the time. I thought it was fabulous but the dill would be just as. I also added a little honey to the dressing as I always do to all my dressings and it was lovely. It just accented the sweetness of the beets and added a touch of extra fragrance.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_03_beet_salad_passionfruit_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beet salad with passionfruit dressing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made one ‘mistake’ though as you may have spotted.  By spooning the dressing on after everything is already plated, you do make the cheese turn quite a bright yellow. It doesn’t do anything to the flavour but aesthetically you might not like that, so the alternative is to toss the beets with the dressing before plating and then top with the cheese. So you live you learn!! What if you don’t have goat cheese or don’t like it – this salad would be equally delicious with feta but will loose the creaminess of the goat cheese. It’s a good alternative though. I’m sure you will love this very sophisticated salad.  I loved the dressing and it’s crazy that I never thought to use passion fruit in it – it’s the perfect balance of acidity with a touch of sweetness and all that wonderful flavour. I will definitely be making it again. Enjoy!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_03_beet_salad_passionfruit_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beet salad with passionfruit dressing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 small to medium beets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 passion fruit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp of olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp of honey or maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper to taste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100 grams of goat cheese crumbled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chopped mint for garnish (chopped dill as an alternative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_03_beet_salad_passionfruit_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beet salad with passionfruit dressing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the beets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preheat the oven to 350 ° F&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Wrap each individual beet in foil and place on a baking sheet and roast for approx 1 hour or until they are cooked through – test by sticking them with a sharp knife.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once they are done let them cool as they are wrapped and on the baking sheet&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once they are cool enough to handle peel them by squeezing the skin off - it should come off quite easily. Any parts that are difficult to come off you can trim off with a knife or a peeler. Then chop them into bite sized pieces and plate.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the passion fruit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cut them in half and scrape the insides of the fruit onto a mesh sieve over a bowl to catch all the juice. Once in the sieve used the back of a spoon to swirl the seeds around pressing them against the sieve to release all their juices.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once you have all the juice for the two passion fruit whisk in the honey and olive oil and season dressing with salt and pepper&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Top the beets with the crumbled feta and spoon the dressing over them.  Alternatively you can toss the beets alone with the dressing and then top with the cheese for a prettier finish (cause the cheese will go yellow)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Garnish with the mint and serve
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_03_beet_salad_passionfruit_6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beet salad with passionfruit dressing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/beet-salad-passion-fruit</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/beet-salad-passion-fruit</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Easy To Make Fresh Guacamole</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The one snack I never tire of is chips and dip.  Crispy salty chips that are really a mode to getting more of that dip in your mouth. My favourite combo is tortilla chips and guacamole. I could make this creamy delicious dip any day of the year back home having avocados available all year round, so you understand why I treasure each one of them here and crave guacamole so badly.  The avocados we have here are absolutely delicious and huge. Are they perfect for guacamole? Not really but they still make a yummy one and I will take what I can get.  Ours are a little on the sweeter side and they have a higher water content.  I love them nevertheless and I will always work with what I have available.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_01_guacamole_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guacamole&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally the Hass variety of avocados are the best for making a nice guacamole. They have to be nice and ripe – so dark colour skin and soft to the touch.  And the key to a great guacamole in my opinion is that you need the freshest ingredients. I don’t want to say ‘in my opinion’ throughout the whole post so when I state something about guacamole preference, it’s just that – my preference and my opinion.  I’m not the authority on guac or its authenticity. I’m just sharing how I love it.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_01_guacamole_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guacamole&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fresh ingredients are a must, and lots of lime to add lots of flavour to keep your beautiful dip from turning brown.  If you’re making it ahead and worried about oxidation, lots of lime is the solution, as well as storing it in an airtight container with a few of the pits or seeds of the avo smushed in the dip. (Make sure to remove them before serving though) Another tip I have heard of but not tried is adding a ½ inch layer of water over the dip while it’s sitting in the fridge in a sealed container and then tipping the water out and stirring the guac before serving. The thin layer of water acts as a barrier to prevent oxidation.  Whenever I make it, it’s gone way before that happens so I don’t usually worry about that.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_01_guacamole_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guacamole&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-add-in-or-not-to-add-in&quot;&gt;To add in or not to add in&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recipe below is how I make it always.  I don’t add sour cream or mayo or any thing like that.  I actually don’t even add tomatoes which many people love to add to it. Just my choice. I find they get a little soggy and I dislike the texture of them in it.  If you don’t mind the texture of them in your guacamole then they are definitely a great add in.  A few other things I add sometimes are a clove of garlic grated, chopped green onions or chives and extra peppers for more heat and flavour.  If I’m organized and plan ahead I even like to roast my garlic and jalapeños which adds a smoky and fabulous flavour to the guacamole. Cilantro or Chadon Beni is a must! That’s one ingredient I insist on – without it, it just ain’t guac!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_01_guacamole_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guacamole&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lets-talk-about-texture&quot;&gt;Let’s talk about texture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texture is completely all preference. Some like it super smooth and done in a food processor but I personally like it creamy but still chunky so I do the smashing with a fork which allows you to control how smooth or chunky you want it. There you have it! Grab some avocados and make some of this glorious dip and enjoy it snacking on the couch and catching up on your Netflix, or if you’re like me while finishing up work in front of my computer. Either way enjoy!!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_01_guacamole_6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guacamole&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-4 of our local avocados or approx 5 ripe haas variety avocados&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Juice of two limes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ of a red onion chopped chopped finely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¾ cup loosely packed cilantro, Chadon Beni chopped finely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-2 jalapeños seeds removed and chopped finely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt to taste&lt;br /&gt;
(For more add-ins check the post above)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cut each avocado open, remove pit (save pit if making a head and storing in guac) scoop out the avocado into a bowl and squeeze juice from one of the limes all over the avocados and this will help prevent browning. Use a fork to mash them into the consistency you like.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stir in gently the the onions, jalapeños and cilantro.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Squeeze in the juice of the second lime and season well with salt to taste - stirring guac gently to combine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Serve with your fav tortilla chips, or with tacos, burritos or literally slathered onto anything and enjoy!!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_12_01_guacamole_7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Guacamole&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guacamole</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guacamole</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smoky Fish Tacos With Tangy Slaw And A Coconut Lime Cilantro Sauce</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tacos make me very happy! I’m a fan of all- soft, hard, chicken, pork, beef, and as you can tell fish as well. I love all things wrapped, folded and layered so tacos are definitely a welcome favourite each week in our home. Simply put these fish tacos are mouthwateringly delicious. You can use any type of firm white fish you have available, and this rub is a wonderful one to have on hand which really works well with seafood in general. I have used it in other fish recipes as well as a shrimp rub too.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_11_28_fish_tacos_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fish Tacos With Coconut Lime Cilantro Sauce&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slaw is a must and you can use it with any type of tacos you make.  It adds a zesty crunch and acidity that I love to my tacos.   That creamy coconut lime cilantro sauce aka  ‘green sauce’ is also great with all sorts of tacos too, but I especially love it with shrimp and fish tacos. It’s fresh creamy and oh so flavourful! This is a quick and easy recipe for any day of the week and I know you guys will love it!
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_11_28_fish_tacos_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fish Tacos With Coconut Lime Cilantro Sauce&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-fish&quot;&gt;For the fish&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 firm white fish fillets (I used tilapia)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ tsp cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp onion powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp dry mustard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ tsp brown sugar /coconut sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-3 tbsp olive oil
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Combine all the spices and empty onto a plate or shallow bowl. Dredge the fish and rub the spices into it both sides and set aside&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat a large size pan and olive oil to medium heat and sauté the fish fillets for a few minutes on each side until done. Remove and cut in half and tent with foil while preparing to assemble tacos
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-slaw&quot;&gt;For the slaw&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients-1&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup finely sliced or shredded red cabbage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup finely sliced or shredded white cabbage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;¼ cup of cilantro or Chadon Beni chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 clove of garlic grated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Juice from 2 limes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup Greek yoghurt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp of jalapeños in brine chopped (or one fresh jalapeño or hot pepper seeds removed and chopped finely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp honey or maple syrup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper to taste
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions-1&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all ingredients in a large bowl and massage well for all the flavours to combine and refrigerate while making the fish to allow the flavours to develop further&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_11_28_fish_tacos_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fish Tacos With Coconut Lime Cilantro Sauce&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-coconut-lime-cilantro-sauce&quot;&gt;For the coconut lime cilantro sauce&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients-2&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup cilantro or Chandon Beni&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;½ cup sliced green onion or chives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 jalapeño pepper or your choice of hot pepper seeds removed and chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup coconut milk or cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Juice from 1 lime&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper to taste
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;directions-2&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a food processor pulse the cilantro, green onions, jalapeño, and garlic until finely chopped. Add the coconut milk and lime juice and pulse until combined and creamy. Season with salt and pepper to taste
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-serve-and-assemble-tacos&quot;&gt;To serve and assemble tacos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 small tortillas (toasted in a large pan or left as is according to preference)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chopped tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crumbled cotija cheese or feta&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Extra lime wedges&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top each tortilla with fish, slaw, sauce and chopped tomatoes and crumbled cheese. Serve with extra lime wedges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/2017_11_28_fish_tacos_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fish Tacos With Coconut Lime Cilantro Sauce&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/fish-tacos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/fish-tacos</guid>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
